<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The MindBike® - A new brainer :: Mindbike Learning Systems LLC</title>
    <link>https://www.mindbike.net/index.html</link>
    <description>Several years ago I received a call from a special education teacher that changed my practice for the next 20 years. I am a physical therapist in the public school system and have been since the late 1980s. &#34; Mr. Wray, something is happening with that student that you put on the stationary bike. If they pedal for 15 minutes they can motor plan to make a sandwich, if they don’t pedal for 15 minutes they can’t make the sandwich.&#34; That teenage student had a brain injury that was several years old and had NOT responded to standard physical therapy treatment. I had purchased a commercial stationary bike with reciprocal upper and lower extremity movement that mimicked a crawling movement in hopes that it would help this student’s poor bilateral coordination and processing. After a few weeks of riding the bike, not only could they make a sandwich but this student could also perform a jumping jack. So both fine and gross motor coordination were improved from simply riding this bike long enough.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mindbike.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MindBikes and Learning Disabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.mindbike.net/mindbike/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mindbike.net/mindbike/index.html</guid>
      <description>Most of the children I work with in the school systems are in self-contained special education classrooms. These students are not able to learn effectively in a regular classroom and need more on one and small-group instruction. Physical Therapy is a related service added to help children benefit from their education. Two students in particular helped me realize that riding the “ Mindbike” was helping these students perform better not just physically but academically.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>